Hello everyone, welcome back to another great lesson here with us at English Pod, my name is Marco and I'm
Erica and today we're going to be getting money. That's right. We're going to have a lesson about the ATM,
the ATM or automatic teller machine. Okay. That's what it stands for ATM. So we're going to be looking at
the language that you'll probably find in an ATM maybe in the United States or in English speaking country.
That's right, but before
we begin, why don't we look
at some vocabulary that
we'll hear in the dialogue.
Very cablery preview.
As we mentioned, the ATM
or automatic teller machine
is a machine where you get
your money, right? Exactly.
And also, well, some people or in
different places, they may call it the bank
machine. Yeah, or maybe the cash machine
or just a money machine or something.
All right, so ATM ATM and now
let's take a look at our next word.
Local authorities, the local
authorities, the local authorities.
So what are the local authorities? Well,
basically it's the police, the police. Why do
you say local authorities? Okay. Well, authority
is the person in charge, right? The boss.
So the local authorities are basically
the people who are the boss of
this place in that area. Yeah. So
the police, the local authorities.
So why don't we start
now with our dialogue?
Why are we talking about local
authorities and ATM machines?
I don't know. We got a listen to find out.
Stupid girl making me spend so much money.
Now I have to get it from the ATM.
Hello, welcome to Universal
Bank. Please insert your
card into the slot. I know
what I put in my card.
Stupid machine talking me like I'm
an idiot. Please input your six digit,
pink code followed by the pound
key. Thank you. Please select an option.
Thank you. You have
selected withdraw.
Yeah, yeah, I know what I
selected. Just give me my money.
Please type the amount you would like to
withdraw. Thank you. You want to transfer.
$10,000 U.S. dollars to the
World Wildlife Foundation. If this is
correct, please press one. No, no.
Stupid machine. What are you doing? No.
Confirmed. Thank
you for using our bank.
Please remove your card
from the slot. Goodbye.
No, way. What happened? Give me my money.
Danger. Danger. The exits have been
sealed and adores will remain locked until
the local authorities arrive. Thank
you for using our bank. Have a nice day.
No.
All right. So it's not his
day today. I think he was
very unlucky and maybe
he's going to be in trouble.
I know. And he was on a
date. This is probably one of the
worst things that can happen
to a guy when he's on a date.
All right. Yeah. So well, we
saw some of the language
that was related to an
ATM money and banking.
So why don't we take a look at
that now in language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
All right. So the guy had to
insert his card into the slot.
Okay. So slot slot. All right, slot.
And that is an opening right
or a type of hole maybe. Yeah.
It's a hole that is usually long
long and it's like a rectangular hole.
Yeah. It's a slot is never a circle.
Okay. So for example, when you
get mail, the mailman will put it
into your mailbox through the slot.
That's right. Okay.
And now that he put his card into the
slot, he had to input a six digit pin code.
Want to just do both
together? Digit and pin code.
Yeah. Okay. So a
six digit pin code.
All right. Now we have
two words here that are new.
Digit. Digit is basically a
number between zero and nine.
Okay. So any number between zero
and nine is considered a digit. Yes.
So 100 is made up of three digits. Three
digits. Okay. And what about pin code?
A pin code is your secret number
that you used to take money out.
Now, why wouldn't we say password?
Password is usually letters. Okay.
And pin code is numbers.
Exactly. All right.
He had to input
his six digit pin code.
And then after that, he
had to press the pound key.
Pound key. Now this
is strange. A pound key.
What is that? Well, you know
on a phone on the bottom right.
Uh huh. There's a key or a button that
looks like a number sign. Number sign.
So kind of like two vertical
lines and two horizontal lines.
Yeah. Two lines going up and
down two lines going across.
Okay. So that's called the pound key. Mm
hmm. All right. What about the other one?
It's called the star. The star key.
The star key. All right.
So after the pin code, after the pound key,
now he's ready to withdraw money. Mm hmm.
So we heard withdrawal.
Okay. So withdrawal is a noun.
It's the action of taking money out.
Okay. A withdrawal. A withdrawal. Okay.
And two withdrawal. Two withdrawal is just
the verb to take out money, right? Exactly.
So we have the noun and the verb. The
only difference is an L at the end. Yes.
So withdrawal noun and withdraw verb. Okay.
And well, he wanted to withdraw
money, but something happened with
the ATM and it turned out that he
was going to transfer money. Uh oh.
So transfer transfer transfer.
When you transfer money,
you take it from one place
and put it in another. Okay.
And usually in banking,
when you transfer
money, you don't really
see it, right? Exactly.
The electronics. So you just
put it from one bank account
to another, but you never
actually see this money.
Exactly. So transfer money
transfer. And now this one also has
a verb and a noun, right?
Right. A transfer and two transfer.
Same word. Yeah.
Easy. All right.
So why don't we listen to our
dialogue for the second time.
It's going to be slowed
down a little bit and
then we'll come back
and look at some phrases.
Stupid girl making me spend so much money.
Now I have to get it from the ATM.
Hello. Welcome to Universal Bank.
Please insert your card into the slot.
I know what I put in my card. Stupid
machine talking to me like I'm an idiot.
Please input your six digit pin
code followed by the pound key.
Thank you. Please select
an option. Thank you.
You have selected
withdrawal. Yeah. Yeah.
I know what I selected.
Just give me my money.
Please type the amount you would like to
withdraw. Thank you. You want to transfer.
10,000 U.S. dollars. Two. The
World Wildlife Foundation. If this is
correct, please press one. No. No.
Stupid machine. What are you doing? No.
Confirmed. Thank you for using our bank.
Please remove your card from the slot.
Goodbye. No way. What
happened? Give me my money.
Danger. Danger. The exits have been sealed
and the doors will remain locked until
the local authorities arrive. Thank you
for using our bank. Have a nice day. No.
Okay. So that was a little easier to understand.
But Marco, there's some interesting phrases
here. Some instructions that you commonly
read or hear when you're using a bank machine.
So why don't we take a look at these phrases
and fluency builder. Fluency builder.
Well, the bank machine told
this guy to insert your card.
Insert your card.
So this verb to insert
to place inside. Exactly.
So what else can we insert? Well, for
example, commonly you insert a disk.
Yeah, in your computer. In your
computer. Yeah. Or maybe insert
a CD into your CD player or
DVD into your DVD player. Yeah.
All right.
So to insert something to put inside. Yes.
So he had to insert
his card into the slot.
And then the bank machine asked
him to select an option. Select an option.
Now this is a very common phrase that you will not
only see in 18 years, but basically everywhere,
right? Like in computers or the internet or many,
many things where you're dealing with machines.
So it's an order that says,
well, select one of these
choices that you have. Make
a choice. Make a choice. Yeah.
Select an option. All right.
So two simple phrases, but
very useful and also very
high frequency, right? Yeah.
And you know what? When you
use phrases like these two, it sounds
quite professional, doesn't it?
Yeah, a little bit formal. Okay.
So why don't we listen to
our dialogue for the last time
and then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more.
Stupid girl making me spend so much money.
Now I have to get it from the ATM.
Hello. Welcome to
Universal Bank. Please insert
your card into the slot. I
know what I put my card.
Stupid machine talking
me like I'm an idiot.
Please input your six digit pink code
followed by the pound key. Thank you.
Please select an option. Thank
you. You have selected withdraw.
Yeah. Yeah. I know what I
selected. Just give me my money.
Please type the amount you would like to
withdraw. Thank you. You want to transfer.
$10,000 US dollars to the World
Wildlife Foundation. If this is correct,
please press one. No. No. Stupid
machine. What are you doing? No.
Confirmed. Thank you for using our bank.
Please remove your card from the slot.
Goodbye. No way. What happened?
Give me my money.
Danger. Danger. The exits
have been sealed and the doors
will remain locked until
the local authorities arrive.
Thank you for using our bank.
Have a nice day. No.
All right, Erica. So what about you? Have
you ever had any problems with the ATM?
I've had more problems
than I can count.
What happened? Well, I
think in the last two years,
I've probably lost about seven bank cards
in an ATM. Really? You forget it. Yes.
In the slot. I leave it in
the slot and then walk
away from the bank
machine and no bank cards.
Well, I think now the ATM's
because this is a common problem.
Now they have like a little alarm that when
you take out your money and everything,
it just starts beeping and beeping
until you take out your card. Yes.
And I like the bank
machines that actually give
you your card first and
then give you your money.
Because if they give me my
money first, that's all I want, right?
So I run away with my money and
leave my card in the bank machine.
Right. I think that's a good idea.
I've never seen it before though.
It's what's the length
they have been like.
So what about the ATMs that
you only have to swipe your card?
Oh, yeah. I've done that as well
and also ruined a bank card with that.
It's liked it too many
times, put in the wrong
pin code and it blocks
your card. Yeah. Terrible.
Well, what about you guys?
I'm sure everyone has some
experience or some
inconvenience with ATM machines.
So why don't you come to our
website and tell us all about it?
You can also find lots more resources
on our website to help you learn English.
So check it out and
until next time, goodbye.